Survival Is His Revenge
Riddick is a science fiction, action, thriller film directed by David Twohy.
Betrayed by his own kind and left for dead on a desolate planet, Riddick fights for survival
against alien predators and becomes more powerful and dangerous than ever before.
Soon bounty hunters from throughout the galaxy descend on Riddick only to
find themselves pawns in his greater scheme for revenge.
With his enemies right where he wants them, Riddick unleashes a vicious attack of vengeance
before returning to his home planet of Furya to save it from destruction.
Riddick, played by Vin Diesel.
Luna, played by Nolan Gerard Funk.
Boss Johns, played by Matt Nable.
Dahl, played by Katee Sackhoff.
Santana, played by Jordi Mollà.
Diaz, played by Dave Bautista.
Riddick is a 2013 science fiction action film written and directed
by David Twohy, based on the character Richard B.
Riddick by Jim and Ken Wheat.
It is the third installment in The Chronicles of Riddick film series and a sequel
to both Pitch Black (2000) and The Chronicles of Riddick (2004).
Vin Diesel reprises his role as the titular character alongside Jordi Mollà, Matt Nable,
Katee Sackhoff, Dave Bautista, Bokeem Woodbine, Raoul Trujillo, and Karl Urban.
In the film, notorious murderer Riddick is betrayed and left for dead
on a desolate planet and uses his instincts to survive.
He eventually teams up with mercenaries arriving to
capture him to escape from a larger threat.
Riddick was released in the United States on September 6, 2013.
Critics considered it a return to form for the series and it became a
moderate box-office success compared to its predecessor.
A fourth film, entitled Riddick: Furya, is in development.
The film explores themes of dystopia, mercenary, sequel, alien, revenge.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.